<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter>
  <title>Introduction</title>

<para>Welcome to the Open Source Computerized Adaptive Testing System! 
OSCATS aims to be a fully featured engine for writing computerized adaptive
testing (CAT) simulations and can be used as a back-end for operational CAT. 
OSCATS supports both the Item Response Theory (IRT) and cognitively
diagnosis/latent classification psychometric frameworks, including
algorithms for dual-purpose measurement.  The core CAT administration
routine includes eight points for algorithmic customization, and OSCATS
comes ready to be extended with new psychometric models, item selection
algorithms, and statistical calculations.</para>

<para>An OSCATS test is formed by supplying an item bank and a set of
algorithms for item selection, item administration or simulation, and
statistical calculations, such as estimating an examinee's latent ability or
class and tracking item exposure.  These algorithms are
<link linkend="OscatsAlgorithm"><structname>OscatsAlgorithm</structname></link>
objects that attach callback functions to one or more of eight signals
emitted by the
<link linkend="OscatsTest"><structname>OscatsTest</structname></link>
test administration loop.  Items in the bank have a psychometric model in
either the IRT or latent classification framework (or both).  These models
are objects subclassed from the abstract
<link linkend="OscatsContModel"><structname>OscatsContModel</structname></link>
or <link linkend="OscatsDiscrModel"><structname>OscatsDiscrModel</structname></link>
class.  Using new models or algorithms in OSCATS is as simple as writing a
new subclass with the desired functionality.</para>

<para>To get started with OSCATS, it's best to read the documentation for
the test administration loop in <link linkend="oscats-test-administer"><function>oscats_test_administer()</function></link>
and the <link linkend="OscatsTest.signals"><structname>OscatsTest</structname> signals</link>.
Then, take a look at a few of the example programs provided with
OSCATS.  For the specific syntax and semantics of each object, refer to the
complete API documentation.</para>

<para>If you have questions about OSCATS, please do not hesitate to ask them
on the OSCATS mailing list.  And, if you find OSCATS useful in developing
your CAT or conducting CAT research, let us know: We would love to include a
reference to your work on the OSCATS website.</para>

</chapter>
